you are my sworn enemy
вы мой заклятый враг
look at yourself
посмотри на себя
well yes you have a better flag I didn’t
смотрел Ну да у вас флаг получше я не
come
пришла
not worthy to be your enemy
не достоин быть вашим врагом
dirt on our boots it’s worth it so
грязи на наших сапогах это стоит так
ours clung to it we need to wash it forget
наша прицепилась надо его отмыть забыть
because you have no honor
потому что у вас нет ни чести ничего
to be an enemy
чтобы быть врагом
what is
что есть
Russia attacked  with a vile announcement
Россия напала с объявлением подло
Well, the second option is
Ну второй вариант
who are you a person a person I am not a
а кто ты человек человек я не
state
государство
but you have a flag of a person or a state of a
а флаг у тебя человека или государства
[music]
[музыка]
That is, you are now demonstrating the flag of a
То есть ты демонстрируешь сейчас флаг
state yes, that is, you share its
государства да то есть ты разделяешь его
policy No, why did you come to him
политику Нет а зачем ты ему пришла
the state is
государство
interesting If  for example, you were
интересно Если бы у тебя было например
there with an LGBT flag
там флаг ЛГБТ
simply because there is nothing to hang that you
просто потому что нечего повесить что ты
share
разделяешь
But if I didn’t have anything The
Но если бы у меня ничего не было
constitution was opened or something No you are
Конституцией открылась что ли Нет ты же
citizens You know your rights citizens
граждане Ты знаешь свои права у граждан
have rights What are your rights but I have a lot of
есть права Какие твои права но я много
rights for example
прав например
I don’t know there  you have to
Я не знаю там
start with this because
с этого надо и начинать потому что
citizens know their rights And slaves
граждане знают свои права А у холопов
don’t have rights
прав нет
it’s dirt on our feet
это грязь на наших ногах
understood they don’t know rights
понял прав не знает
Here to live You have the right And then
Вот жить Ты имеешь право А дальше
we have the
нам
right to an opinion When was the last time you
право на мнение Когда ты последний раз
exercised the right to an opinion in your country
реализовывал право на мнение
before birth, you can express  your
до рождения можно высказывать свое
opinion from the moment of birth it is no longer possible
мнение с момента рождения уже нельзя
to express your opinion
высказать свое мнение
you don’t have rights you
нет у тебя прав
don’t even have the right to life already
даже право на жизнь нет у тебя уже
because look you are taken and thrown to
потому что смотри вас берут и кидают
fight in a foreign country so that they die there they
воевать в чужую страну чтобы там дохли
took away your right to life if you had it
у вас забрали право на жизнь если она у
while still young  Well, if you grow up to the standard, you
еще молодой Ну Подрастешь до кондиции ты
go to the marketable condition of the cinema, he will come
идешь тогда товарной кондиции кино
up with something new,
новое что-то придумает
maybe
может быть
[music] a
[музыка]
citizen has the right to elect and be
у гражданина есть право избирать и быть
elected, for example,
избранным
[music]
[музыка]
electoral,
избирательная
you have the right to register as
ты имеешь право зарегистрироваться
a deputy,
депутатом
just
просто
a person, for example, for
человек
her, for example, I know
например вот ей например там знаю вот
you there  -something there Navalny wanted
вас какой-то там Навальный хотел
to register as president as a presidential candidate,
зарегистрироваться президент кандидатом
he thought that he was a citizen Yes, he has
он думал что он гражданин Да у него есть
some kind of right
какое-то право
he was given to exercise his right to
ему дали реализовать свое право на
participate in elections
участие в выборах
because he
потому что
didn’t like it,
не нравилось
that is, the right depends on whether
то есть право зависит от того делаешь ли
you do what you like if
то ты то что нравится
if  the realization of your right does not
если если реализация твоего права не
interfere with the goal you have this right if the
мешает цели у тебя это право есть если
realization of your right interferes with you
реализация твоего право мешает у тебя
this right takes away from you a
это право отнимает
citizen It's not just who has a
гражданин Это не просто тут у кого есть
passport the
паспорт
right is also there Seriously
право тоже есть Серьезно
when you and your parents last
когда ты и твои родители последний раз
elected the president
избирали президента
in the last elections I don't remember
на прошлых выборах я не помню
That  there are those elections in which an
То есть это те выборы на которых
independent candidate was not allowed to reach
независимого кандидата не допустили до
Well, Navalny, too, here in 18 he wanted
Ну Навального тоже вот 18 году он хотел
Who was the candidate in the elections only
Кто был из кандидатом на выборах только
some kind of communist Was in short some
коммунист какой-то Был короче какие-то
fake two of these grandfathers to
фейковые два этих деда типа чтобы
be considered true Which one You
считалось правда
don’t even remember exactly how  his
Какой Вот именно даже не помнишь как его
name,
зовут
for example, look, I’m in Ukraine, I can
например смотри я в Украине я могу
even name candidates from the elections that were in
назвать даже с выборов которые были в
the fourteenth year of the presidential elections,
четырнадцатом году президентских могу
because
назвать кандидатов потому что
the majority They really fought for it was
большинство Они реально боролись за
said here that he was sent there
говорилось что его отправили там это
to sit, that is,
посидеть то есть а право слишком много
a citizen does not have the right to talk too much, but
говорить у человека у гражданина нет но
certain things Yes, wait, but you can
определенные вещи Да подожди а можно вас
look for the Constitution what
Конституции искать какие
things are allowed to be said and to what extent,
вещи разрешено говорить и в каком объеме
but you can’t have the
но нельзя
right to freedom of speech,
право на свободу слова
how many words are given there, for example,
она там сколько слов дается например
how many words of a week are given to speak
сколько слов недели дается поговорить
I am given
Мне дают
that Navalny violated
что Навальный нарушил
Navalny wanted to
Навальный хотел
overthrow How If he left in the elections
как свергнуть Как Если ушел на выборах
like him  wanted to overthrow
как он хотел свергнуть
Prigozhin, they just didn’t put him in Well,
Пригожин его как раз не посадили
yes, that is, they didn’t put him inside We
Ну да то есть внутри его не посадили Мы
didn’t even arrest Navalny, but Navalny, who
даже не арестовали а Навальный который
wanted to become president through elections.
хотел через выборы стать президентом Его
there is a citizen has no right
а то есть у гражданина нет права
to speak badly about the president,
говорить плохо о президенте так
but not everything is not all bad precisely because
но не все Не все плохо именно то что
why in America
почему в Америке
citizens can say this fool there [
граждане могут говорить там дурак этот
music]
[музыка]
Why in Ukraine yes citizens can
Почему у нас в Украине да граждане могут
Poroshenko Zelensky is a
там Порошенко дурак Зеленский Почему не
fool  Citizen
могут это говорить А у вас гражданин
Navalny and you and others cannot say
Навальный и ты и другие не могут сказать
bad things about you to the President Why, if he is not citizens, is he the
плохо президенте Почему если не граждане
President
он президент
and why Where does it go,
а почему Куда девается
but only this right to speak about all
но только это право говорить про все
rights,
права
that is, come on, that is, the right to say
то есть давай так то есть право говорить
What you want, you do not have against the President,
Что хочешь у вас нет против Президента
you cannot against the authorities  say something bad
вы не можете против власти что-то плохое
No, I don’t say everything bad,
сказать Нет я же говорю не все плохое
only some specific words
только какие-то определенные слова точно
that can offend for sure, sort of like What
которые могут оскорбить вроде как Какие
words that can offend the authorities
слова которые могут оскорбить власть
can be so you can’t say that
можно так что нельзя говорить что
Navalny was imprisoned For which words,
посадили Навального За какие слова
for example,
например
at least there the first three letters I understood
хотя бы там первые три буквы я понял
what kind of words does it even go there with a letter
каких это слова вообще идет там на букву
for that they imprisoned Navalny
за это посадили Навального
cool, that is, it turns out you
прикольно то есть получается она вас
can say a
можно сказать
citizen can
гражданин может на другого гражданина
say words starting with the letter A to another citizen it’s impossible to say words starting with the letter A to the president
сказать слова на букву А на президента
interesting yes this is an interesting
интересно да вот это интересная
concept of citizenship I like it yes I
концепция гражданства Мне нравится да Я
just thought that citizens elect
просто думал что граждане избирают
If  you want, that is, I was insulted
Если ты хочешь то есть я тут оскорбили
there, the saleswoman in the store said that
там продавщица в магазине сказал то что
you can even the police there, too, really,
ты то можно даже полицию там тоже правда
I think they will go to jail. For example, if something is
я думаю в тюрьму посадят Например если
not quite in your affairs, the
не совсем в ваших делах
right to be elected, you don’t have the right
право избираться у вас нет право
to choose either
выбирать тоже нет
only candidate Putin and two nouns  the
только кандидата Путина и двух ноунеймов
right to express my opinion no
право высказывает свое мнение нет
I'm from Moscow Let's take tomorrow and
Я из Москвы Давайте завтра мы возьмем и
go out just with a white sheet a clean
выйдем просто с белым листочком чистым
white sheet to the center of our city I'm
белым листочком в центр своего города Я
on Independence Square in Khmelnitsky you are
на Майдан Независимости в Хмельницком вы
on Red Square in Moscow and your friend and
на Красную Площадь в Москве и ваш друг и
my friend will film it
мой друг будет снимать это в прямом
live and  let's see who can stand for
эфире и посмотрим кто сможет простоять
14 minutes 88 seconds
14 минут 88 секунд
if there are few people, then it won't work at all,
если мало людей то это вообще Не
because they can do it very
сработает потому что там могут очень
easily. If they
легко Вот если
can, it's very easy to tie
могут Очень просто повязать
a sense.
смысле А что вы хотели сказать
wait, I’ll check Now I’ll check I’ll
нет подождите я проверю Сейчас проверю
see hello Just in case, yes,
посмотрю привет На всякий случай да
google Yes Or you can go out with a white leaflet, I
нагугли Да Или можно с белым листочком
’ll add what you can’t
выходить у вас добавлю то что нельзя
do a
делать
second I
секунду
now have an assistant,
Я сейчас вот у меня есть помощник
I’ll ask her now
я сейчас ее спрошу
that I can’t
что не могу
google
нагуглите
go to the square with a white leaflet Please
выйти на площадь с белым листочком
tell me  what will happen to a Russian
Скажи пожалуйста что будет с россиянином
who comes out with a white piece of paper on
который выйдет с белым листочком на
Red Square to a
Красную Площадь
square with a white one will be put on a White
на площадь с белым посадят на Белую
bottle
бутылку
But it's funny that
Но это прикол в том то что символ же
this symbol means protest What symbol does a
этот обозначает протест Какой символ
white piece of protest paper mean
белый листок бумаги протеста обозначает
seriously
серьезно
And somewhere you count a white piece of paper
А где-то посчитаешь белый лист бумаги
means protest
означает протест
on the Internet, you
в интернете
can’t go out to protest in Russia for the first time and you can’t go out with white sheets
нельзя и выходить с белыми листочками
because the white sheet
нельзя потому что белый листочек
symbolizes The protest of the
символизирует Протест
other side is called that you’ve already
другой стороны зовут что ты уже
started talking that you better switch off
заговорился что тебе лучше отключиться
without a white sheet, you can’t really
без белым листком нельзя он реально
google it or you can go out in Russia with a
гуглил или можно в России выходить с
white sheet, damn it, and
белым листком блин
google it  you can’t google it
причем нагуглил нагуглился нельзя потому
because the white sheet is a symbol of protest
что белый листок это символ протеста
badge
бляха
[music] Like
[музыка]
and donate
Поставьте лайк и
a kilogram right at a time autumn and
донатинами килограмм прям за раз осень а
YouTube’s experience driving us through careers into a
YouTube загоняя нас через карьерки в
shadow ban and there was that video is not
теневый бан и дуже была то видео не
shown to people often
показывается людям часто показывается
information about streams is shown in order to be
информация про стримы для того чтобы
slow  curl
мало оперативный завиток
and ass there
а попок там
video
видео
information and we are with you
информация и мы с вами
[music]
[музыка]